<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Boaz Sobrado&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>http://boazsobrado.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Boaz Sobrado&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 18:51:23 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://boazsobrado.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Raising money for friends hurt by Hurricane Irma</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/10/25/raising-money-for-friends-hurt-by-hurricane-irma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 18:51:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/10/25/raising-money-for-friends-hurt-by-hurricane-irma/</guid>
      <description>For the last year I have been helping people in Cuba sell tourism services online. In practice, this usually means creating accomodation listings on sites like Airbnb, messaging the guests and making sure the money gets to the hosts. About six months into doing this, I discovered a tool called Guesty which made things considerably easier (more on this in a bit).
In September due to Hurricane Irma came. Most guests cancelled their reservations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing a Kalman filter in R for Android GPS measurements</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/08/29/implementing-a-kalman-filter-in-r-for-android-gps-measurements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 17:58:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/08/29/implementing-a-kalman-filter-in-r-for-android-gps-measurements/</guid>
      <description>The problem I downloaded my data from Google Take-Out and have been playing around with it for my thesis. This is roughly what the data looks like after some pre-processing:
  lon lat accuracy    5.115447 52.10574 877  5.115447 52.10574 877  5.113952 52.10451 18  5.115447 52.10574 877  5.115447 52.10574 877  5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 17:14:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>Photograph taken on a trip to Peru and Bolivia by my grandfather and personal photographer Miguel Sobrado
A very short introduction Adventurous Cambridge graduate living the life of a tiring digital nomad. I am working towards a Masters in Statistics and Methodology at Utrecht University. Currently in Singapore on an exchange semester.
Experience working for a bank in Geneva, a private equity advisory firm in London, an agrotech startup in Budapest and an online venture builder in Rangoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Costa Rican Saints</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/08/18/costa-rican-saints/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/08/18/costa-rican-saints/</guid>
      <description>One of the first things a traveller notices when going to Costa Rica is that almost every town or city is named after a Saint. Growing up in Costa Rica, I just assumed this was something true of all Latin American countries, a legacy of Spanish colonial times. California has San Jose, San Fransisco, etc. I thought it was like that from California to Argentina.
After some travelling in Latin America I realised this was simply not true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Images</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/05/22/bayesian-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/05/22/bayesian-images/</guid>
      <description>Graphs to accompany my poster presentation.
The data set The generated data is plotted below: Metropolis Hastings Algorithm This visual explanation of the Metropolis Hastings algorithm shows the proposal and the true density along with the Metropolis Hastings step. It was inspired and adapted from code by Balazs Torok.
Diagnostic Plots for Beta 2 via Gibbs Sampler Autocorrelation Plot The autocorrelations are negligable, suggesting good mixing.
Running Means Plot The running means have settled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thirteen hours in Rotterdam</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/01/11/thirteen-hours-in-rotterdam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 11:32:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/01/11/thirteen-hours-in-rotterdam/</guid>
      <description>Oscar Wilde once wrote:
 “Whenever a man does a thoroughly stupid thing, it is always from the noblest motives.”
 I bought a bus ticket from London to Rotterdam. I did this in order to save what effectively amounts to the price of a handful of beers in London prices. I needed to get to Budapest, and I already had a flight leaving from Rotterdam booked. I spent 8 excruciating hours on a bus from London Victoria to Rotterdam Centraal, to in Rotterdam at 5 am in a cold winter morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are wasting your time with spreadsheets</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/11/13/you-are-wasting-your-time-with-spreadsheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/11/13/you-are-wasting-your-time-with-spreadsheets/</guid>
      <description>This week I had an interesting conversation (as interesting as these conversations can get) about the use of spreadsheets in business. I am still a little bit surprised by how often they are used for things they are not really good for. Now, I don’t want to write about how there are better alternatives to spreadsheets. Instead, I’d like to illustrate how powerful non-spreadsheet tools are by describing a task I completed this week using R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get your Facebook messages into R</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/10/29/how-to-get-your-facebook-messages-into-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/10/29/how-to-get-your-facebook-messages-into-r/</guid>
      <description>It is a truism that we live in the information age, yet on a day to day basis we engage remarkably little with insights on the personal information we create. Sure, Netflix shows you films you want to see, Amazon offers books you want to buy and Facebook shows you pictures of cats with boobs or whatever it is you tend to click on, but explicit purpose of that is to get your money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alphabetically inspired anecdotes from Cuba: 58 years after 1958</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/06/12/alphabetically-inspired-anecdotes-from-cuba-58-years-after-1958/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 11:32:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/06/12/alphabetically-inspired-anecdotes-from-cuba-58-years-after-1958/</guid>
      <description>Aviacion de Cubana There was no toilet paper on the Russian-made Antonov 158 plane which took me and 15 other passengers to Havana. The Cuban state airline, Cubana de Aviacion, clearly does not need have to meet profitability targets. Even the dry sandwich they served tasted of an iron curtain.
Not unlike the other living political museum of China, immigration and customs is relatively straightforward. If you had to guess the political system of a country based on the border control procedures you’d probably guess the United States is authoritarian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I made this website - tutorial</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/04/20/how-i-made-this-website---tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 14:12:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/04/20/how-i-made-this-website---tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Theory As our activities are increasingly organised online – from business through voting to leisure time – knowing how to write (or even just understand) code is an increasingly coveted skill. Its benefits range wide; if you can code you will get a better job, improve your analytical skills, make work processes easier and cheaper.
These reasons led us – Dora and Boaz, authors of this article – to set up our websites as a means of learning and practising a bit of coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boaz&#39;s Review of Books: Violence, elaborate lies and a literary journey through China and Africa</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/04/18/boazs-review-of-books-violence-elaborate-lies-and-a-literary-journey-through-china-and-africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 09:48:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/04/18/boazs-review-of-books-violence-elaborate-lies-and-a-literary-journey-through-china-and-africa/</guid>
      <description>The books I finished reading recently that I thought might be interesting to comment upon were Steven Pinker’s The better Angels of Our Nature, Mo Yan’s Big Breast’s and Wide Hips, Kapuscinski’s The Shadow of the Sun, Robert Mazur’s Infiltrator and David Maurer’s Big Con . Steven Pinker, a psychologist at Harvard, wrote a (way too long) book to argue the world is becoming less, not more violent. What about ISIS, Ukraine, gang warfare and mass shootings?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump and Zuckerberg&#39;s Matrix</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/02/29/donald-trump-and-zuckerbergs-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/02/29/donald-trump-and-zuckerbergs-matrix/</guid>
      <description>Prediction markets have the Republican nomination for President of the USA going to billionaire reality TV host and megalomaniac Donald Trump. On the other side of the aisle, self-described socialist Sanders is making Hillary Clinton’s campaign sweat. This isn’t “politics as usual” for anyone except the writers of The Simpsons. According to the party decides theory (or at least my interpretation of Nate Silver’s interpretation) the party, as a loose coalition of opinion forming individuals, can heavily weigh in on who gets nominated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boaz&#39;s Review of Books</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/02/17/boazs-review-of-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/02/17/boazs-review-of-books/</guid>
      <description>A few books I recently finished reading are Ben Bernanke&amp;rsquo;s Courage to act, Dr Philip Tetlock&amp;rsquo;s Superforecasting, Peter Thiel’s Zero to One, an unofficial biography on George Soros, and collection of druggie short stories titled Acid House by Irvine Welsh. I do not expect to do justice to the arguments in the books (read a real book review if you want that), I&amp;rsquo;m just sharing the lessons I learned from them as a little exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read in 2015</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/12/27/what-i-read-in-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/12/27/what-i-read-in-2015/</guid>
      <description>I bought my Kindle slightly over a year ago, and since it has accompanied me everywhere I&amp;rsquo;ve been. It has provided me with entertainment on long journeys and education in subjects where I had none. I would like to share some of my favourite quotes. I have sorted them based on when I started reading them, with some slight editing.
December (2014) ﻿The Prince (Niccolò Machiavelli) Besides, pretexts for taking away the property are never wanting; for he who has once begun to live by robbery will always find pretexts for seizing what belongs to others; but reasons for taking life, on the contrary, are more difficult to find and sooner lapse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where I slept in 2015</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/12/22/where-i-slept-in-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/12/22/where-i-slept-in-2015/</guid>
      <description>This year has been an adventure. I&amp;rsquo;ve been on three continents, countless countries and dozens of cities. I thought it would be an interesting project to quantify it all by visualising on a map the places where I slept. This is the result: In case you are interested in how I did it you can find the code below. I was inspired by this blog post.
library(readr) library(ggmap) library(&amp;quot;shiny&amp;quot;) days&amp;lt;-read_csv(&amp;quot;daysinayear/days.csv&amp;quot;)# spreadsheet with place in one column and days slept in another devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;bwlewis/rthreejs&amp;quot;) #First step: get lat and lng for where I&#39;ve slept using Google Maps API x&amp;lt;-geocode(days$Location) days&amp;lt;-cbind(days,x) # Make a cool spinning globe globejs(img=&amp;quot;http://2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Migrant Crisis and Demography</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/11/05/the-migrant-crisis-and-demography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/11/05/the-migrant-crisis-and-demography/</guid>
      <description>In September, images of anti-riot police in a standoff with desperate migrants were shown on television, inspiring many people to volunteer and even more people to chatter about the situation. Yet the problem with our handling of crises is that we often wait for one to happen before doing anything (even just notice something is amiss). Humans are vulnerable to overlooking gradual phenomena with no easily distinguishable onset. There is an ongoing global demographic transition and it will influence most shifts in the next 25 years, be it in politics, business or international relations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Google Maps API: Mol Bubi Competition</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/11/05/using-google-maps-api-mol-bubi-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 11:36:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/11/05/using-google-maps-api-mol-bubi-competition/</guid>
      <description>A few friends and I are involved in the Budapest public bicycle data science competition. As of right now we are in the top ten, although in all honesty, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t really started yet. We signed a non-disclosure agreement, so I cannot really share any cool details. What I can share however, is the function I wrote in R to get calculate the distances and duration of bike trips using Google Maps&amp;rsquo; API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar 2015</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/10/26/myanmar-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 11:36:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/10/26/myanmar-2015/</guid>
      <description>I spent six amazing months in Myanmar (Burma). Here&amp;rsquo;s a video of my adventures with monkeys, monks and motorcycles.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do stupid people make more spelling mistakes? An analysis with R.</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/10/20/do-stupid-people-make-more-spelling-mistakes-an-analysis-with-r./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 10:23:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/10/20/do-stupid-people-make-more-spelling-mistakes-an-analysis-with-r./</guid>
      <description>English orthography is a tricky topic. Most people learning English (and a great number of native speakers) are puzzled by a written language with an utter disregard for phonemic representation. It is therefore very worrying that individuals intuitively assume making orthographic mistakes is a sign of low intelligence or unprofessionalism. In this post we are going to show how we looked into the relationship of IQ and orthography using R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t fear foreign education</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2012/11/20/dont-fear-foreign-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2012/11/20/dont-fear-foreign-education/</guid>
      <description>Startling new data show that emigration out of Hungary is at a 20-year record high and that many more Hungarians have seriously considered leaving Hungary to live, work, or study in another member state of the EU. But instead of speaking ominously about the potentially catastrophic consequences of such emigration trends for Hungary, it is useful to think of this increased mobility as a potentially positive phenomenon.
Geographic mobility is often an indicator of social mobility.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>