<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Literature on Boaz Sobrado&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>http://boazsobrado.com/tags/literature/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Literature on Boaz Sobrado&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://boazsobrado.com/tags/literature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Boaz&#39;s Review of Books: Violence, elaborate lies and a literary journey through China and Africa</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/04/18/boazs-review-of-books-violence-elaborate-lies-and-a-literary-journey-through-china-and-africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 09:48:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/04/18/boazs-review-of-books-violence-elaborate-lies-and-a-literary-journey-through-china-and-africa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The books I finished reading recently that I thought might be interesting to comment upon were Steven Pinker’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/The_Better_Angels_of_Our_Nature&#34;&gt;The better Angels of Our Nature&lt;/a&gt;, Mo Yan’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Big_Breasts_and_Wide_Hips&#34;&gt;Big Breast’s and Wide Hips&lt;/a&gt;,  Kapuscinski’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/The_Shadow_of_the_Sun&#34;&gt;The Shadow of the Sun&lt;/a&gt;, Robert Mazur’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6657841-the-infiltrator&#34;&gt;Infiltrator&lt;/a&gt; and David Maurer’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/403452.The_Big_Con&#34;&gt;Big Con&lt;/a&gt; .
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Steven Pinker, a psychologist at Harvard, wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/review/R2F21HEM6W56FI/ref=cm_cr_dp_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=0141034645&amp;amp;channel=detail-glance&amp;amp;nodeID=266239&amp;amp;store=books&#34;&gt;(way too long)&lt;/a&gt; book to argue the world is becoming less, not more violent. What about ISIS, Ukraine, gang warfare and mass shootings? Terrible things, but not nearly as violent as the Thirty Year War or Genghis Khan. This is based on relative homicide rates, or simply put: how many people die a violent death as a percentage of the population. You might be one of those paleo diet people who idealises the “peaceful” times of back when we were hunter-gatherers, living in the comfort of nature eating fruits off trees and fish out of the water. It turns out that was the most violent time we ever lived. In fact, even in the last 50 years there has been a substantial decrease in violence in the world. Even terrorism isn’t what it &lt;a href=&#34;http://globalriskinsights.com/2016/03/19640/&#34;&gt;used to be&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://i0.wp.com/globalriskinsights.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/terrorist_attacks_in_western_europe_since_1970_n-557x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;terrorist attacks in Europe&#34; /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pinker goes through a list of everyday occurrences in medieval and hunter-gatherer lives: from infanticide to torture, rape and genocide, a list so gruesome and at times detailed that reading it I felt like a tabloid reader. Apparently we’ve barely found well preserved archaeological finding of someone that was not murdered or seriously maimed. So why have we started to murder, torture and rape each other less? Pinker proposes two reasons: first the rise and consolidation of the modern state. In this he relies strongly on the philosophy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Thomas_Hobbes&#34;&gt;Thomas Hobbes&lt;/a&gt;,  arguing that the states are Leviathans whose net effect is to protect against violence by monopolising it. The second reason for the decline of violence is the establishment of non-violent cultural norms, a type of self-domestication, which slowly teach us that violence isn’t acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author goes into substantially more detail into the philosophical and empirical reasoning behind his arguments, including a categorisation of violence types and its separate causes. For instance, passion violence is less likely to be diminished by states than reputational violence. It makes sense to have a “nobody mess with me” reputation, when it keeps you alive in the anarchic state of nature. It makes less sense to smack someone on the street for looking at you funny for it will land you in jail. Pinker also sprinkles the book full of quaint quotes to prove his point:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Civilized men are more discourteous than savages because they know they can be impolite without having their skulls split.” – Robert E. Howard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the author does realise that states are not a panacea: they also kill loads of people themselves when they clash with each other or experience internal unrest. As for changes in culture, Pinker claims they are responsible for a relatively recent decrease in violence. Hitting your wife and kids was acceptable in the Western world a century ago, but now isn’t. In medieval times a popular sport was cat baiting: a cat was tied down and people would try to head-butt it to death with their hands tied behind their backs, risking nasty injuries for all involved parties. As fun as it sounds, it is now unacceptable, along with duelling, torture and slavery. One of the most interesting points raised looks at the relationship between utensils, particularly knives, and the culture of violence. He claims it is not coincidental that in China, the place with a 5000 year of statehood, knives have been relegated to the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet China in the 20th century is a great showcase of violence. It illustrates what happens when two states clash, when a state breaks down in Civil War and the subsequent heavy-handed reconsolidation. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Big_Breasts_and_Wide_Hips&#34;&gt;Big Breast’s and Wide Hips&lt;/a&gt; is a detailed account of the life of a Chinese family through those turbulent times. It reminded me slightly of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/320.One_Hundred_Years_of_Solitude&#34;&gt;One Hundred Years of Solitude&lt;/a&gt; and its magical realism  (although this may be simply because I was unable to remember the dozens of similar sounding names in both novels). The main character and narrator is a weak but enduring boy infatuated with breasts, much to the disappointment of his mother, a long suffering matriarch with bound feet. Nevertheless, the fortune of the family and the boy goes up and does along the epochs, mostly depending on whether the political situation is favourable to them. I enjoy Mo Yan’s books because they are highly entertaining and captivating while at the same time lending outsiders an insight into the Chinese mind and the suffering of the 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where there&amp;rsquo;s life, death is inevitable. Dying&amp;rsquo;s easy; it&amp;rsquo;s living that&amp;rsquo;s hard. The harder it gets, the stronger the will to live. And the greater the fear of death, the greater the struggle to keep on living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a sense, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/The_Shadow_of_the_Sun&#34;&gt;The Shadow of the Sun&lt;/a&gt; aims to do a similar thing by describing the turbulent times Africa was going through after the process of decolonialisation through the eyes of a Polish correspondent. However, as an outsider, Kapuscinski does not speak authentically for the African mind, nor does he attempt to. Instead, he excels at describing, explaining and dispelling myths about Africa. This includes the notion that Africa exists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Only with the greatest of simplifications, for the sake of convenience, can we say Africa. In reality, except as a geographical term, Africa doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kapuscinski’s language is picturesque, his understanding is highly empathetic and his essays betray his education as a historian. Through his anecdotes one gains an understanding not only of the violent calamities that befell millions of Africans in the 20th century, but also of the trivialities of history and everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History is so often the product of thoughtlessness: it is the offspring of human stupidity, the fruit of benightedness, idiocy, and folly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Mo Yan and Kapuscinski are adept at illustrating not only how folly makes history but also the Hobbesian argument espoused by Pinker: when a state falls power goes to the warlords and levels of violence creep up. Both in China and in Africa there is truth in Kapuscinski&amp;rsquo;s eloquent phrase:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For the law in force here is this: whoever has weapons eats first.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet there are fundamental differences, and it is here that the nuance in Pinker’s argument becomes apparent. In the Chinese case the population is docile and acceptant of the state, and the warlords for the most part accept the responsibility of having to govern, even if the practice is less than perfect. This is perhaps best evidenced in the beginning of Mo Yan’s novel, as Japanese forces approach Northern Gaomi county, the Shangguan family ask’s itself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why should we flee? We are not landholders nor officials.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not think Liberian civilians would ask a similar question. They know perfectly well why they must flee, for African warlords fight not for power over the state (thus looking for the oligarchs and the high level bureaucrats) but for booty. They still follow the old adage attributed to Genghis Khan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greatest joy for a man is to defeat his enemies, to drive them before him, to take from them all they possess, to see those they love in tears, to ride their horses, and to hold their wives and daughters in his arms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In nations where the state did not exist it must be built, and that it a long and bloody process. State building in Africa is further complicated by the legacy of colonial extractive states, which are designed to amass wealth first and to keep the peace second. Kapuscinski himself says it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colonial origins of the African state—a state wherein the civil servant received renumeration beyond all measure and reason—ensured that in independent Africa, the struggle for power instantly assumed an extremely fierce and ruthless character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas in China you could get rich through commerce no matter who was in power, as long as you did not stand in their way, in many African states the only way to riches was political. And many of the men who later became despots had nothing to lose, coming from disenfranchised minority groups, living in shantytowns in cities which had little to offer them. Moreover, in China the calamities of the 20th century interregnum were viewed as extraordinary, whilst in many of the African states it is business as usual. In fact, in the words of Kapuscinski:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people here treat political cataclysms—coups d’état, military takeovers, revolutions, and wars—as phenomena belonging to the realm of nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another fine example of a state having its power tested was Colombia in the 1980’s, the days when Pablo Escobar spent $10000 a year on rubber bands to keep his dollar bills neatly organised. These are the days in which Robert Mazur’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6657841-the-infiltrator&#34;&gt;Infiltrator&lt;/a&gt; is set (which will also be a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1355631/&#34;&gt;film&lt;/a&gt; later this year). In this book Robert tells how he took down the Bank of Credit and Commerce International, a well-known international bank with 30000 employees and 400 branches worldwide.  Mazur convincingly points out that the weakness of all organised crime is its purse, be it corrupt government officials in Nigeria, thieving despots in Liberia or Mexican drug traffickers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greatest weakness the drug trade has is banking relationships. Each dirty banker serves dozens of big-time traffickers, but those bankers don’t have the stomach to sit in prison for life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authorities catch very little of it. In the book Mazur breathtakingly explains the extent to which he had to make personal sacrifices, such as financing the operation out of his own personal funds, with an increasingly unhelpful institutional apparatus behind him in order to bring down the big time money launderers. Funnily enough, when he got very high up and was dining with bank CEO’s openly discussing laundering cocaine money, the whole institutional apparatus became very unhelpful. In fact:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…we [Mazur &amp;amp; co] could trust our targets in the case more than our own people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mazur also hints to the why: at the very top of the game people are very much connected, the owners of the banks fly with the presidents of the US. Normally I would dismiss such a statement as a conspiracy lunacy, but this is a guy who spent three years undercover as a money launderer after all, and did take down a large bank. In fact, the recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://panamapapers.icij.org/&#34;&gt;Panama Papers&lt;/a&gt; leak reinforces it, who would have thought that the same law firm is used by David Cameron, the Icelandic prime minister and notorious Mexican drug dealers? Of course, Pinker would also have an opinion: states are there first to control the peace, policy is more of a recent hobby. Arresting the gangbangers on the street is much more important than touching the men leading the Cartels. Mazur recognizes this is explicitly part of the policy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managers are rated and promoted on the number of arrests and seizures made by their agents[…] It is a lot easier to assign agents to many little cases that result in the arrest, prosecution, and conviction of minor criminals. This is one of the reasons why the War on Drugs will always be unwinnable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the War on Drugs is unwinnable, what about ongoing efforts against on money laundering? Surely after 2008 no bank would dare to engage in money laundering?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BCCI got caught. Only that detail separates them from the rest of the international banking community. They’ve been out of the game for twenty years. The drug trade has produced about $500 billion per year since then, but no one has been prosecuted for laundering those $10 trillion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Mazur took down BCCI, pretty much all major banks have been implicated in money laundering scandals. Apparently, there is very little that states will do to get rid of these criminals. Unless of course, the Cartels are openly trying to take over the state, which is precisely what is happening in many parts of the world.  The power of the Cartels is such that when &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Manuel_Noriega&#34;&gt;Manuel Noriega&lt;/a&gt;, the de facto leader of the sovereign state of Panama, was running into trouble with US authorities for money laundering (sound familiar?) the Ochoa family sent him a little coffin with a note warning him that he would be able to use it if any of Jorge’s money was lost in Panama. The note was signed “The Ochoa Family”.  In the end of course, the US toppled both the Medellin Cartel and the Panamanian government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in the topic of infiltrating drug organisations you should read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Dark-Art-Undercover-Narco-terrorism/dp/1592408931&#34;&gt;The Dark Art&lt;/a&gt;, a biographical account by a more gung-ho DEA agent who was very active internationally, tracking down traffickers from the Burmese Golden Triangle, to Ciudad Juarez and Afghanistan. If on the other hand you are interested in the details of money laundering, I highly recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22836908-criminal-capital&#34;&gt;Criminal Capital&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money launderers belong to the subset of criminals which do not use violence, called grifters in American argot. According to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/David_W._Maurer&#34;&gt;David Maurer&lt;/a&gt;, in the hierarchy of crime in the early 20th century US, con men were at the top. I was inspired to read into the topic by the two aforementioned agents who spent years pretending to be someone they are not and by Better Call Saul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height =&#34;350&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/coFufx4Vt3o&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Big Con is written by a linguist and details how cons work. Not only that, it provides an incredible insight into the lives and language of criminals in the US before World War 2. It shows the reader how these criminals identify and lure the mark:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Never interrupt a fink while he is talking. Be a good listener and he will immediately conclude that you are a young man of some note. Just listen carefully to the lies he tells you. Marks are chock full of lies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It explains how they gain their trust to convince them to do some unethical or illegal deal that will pay off greatly. Of course, it will pay off greatly only to the con men. Through the lens of these criminals you get an entire sociography of the incredibly corrupt American society that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/211376.Theodore_Roosevelt&#34;&gt;Roosevelt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Andrew-Carnegie-David-Nasaw/dp/0143112449&#34;&gt;Carnegie&lt;/a&gt; knew, in which ethnicities and social classes are ranked based on how hard they are to scam:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jews are difficult, but there is a con man&amp;rsquo;s proverb which says, &amp;ldquo;It takes ten Jews to trim one Greek.&amp;rdquo; And all con men agree that it is next to impossible to trim a Chinese. &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know any grifter who would be dumb enough to try to trim a Chink”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think that I would be hard to scam, but of course, so do most people. Thousands of people (and a few of my friends) have gotten scammed on the internet, subsequently getting very little support from the authorities. If Pinker&amp;rsquo;s thesis is correct, we&amp;rsquo;ll see more scams and less muggings in the future. Will states be able to adapt to these new challenges, or will they be inefficiently prosecuted like money laundering is?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boaz&#39;s Review of Books</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/02/17/boazs-review-of-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/02/17/boazs-review-of-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few books I recently finished reading are Ben Bernanke&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/10/25/books/review/ben-bernankes-the-courage-to-act.html&#34;&gt;Courage to act&lt;/a&gt;, Dr Philip Tetlock&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/news/books-and-arts/21666098-forecasting-talent-luckily-it-can-be-learned-unclouded-vision&#34;&gt;Superforecasting&lt;/a&gt;,  Peter Thiel’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://zerotoonebook.com/&#34;&gt;Zero to One&lt;/a&gt;, an unofficial biography on George Soros, and collection of druggie short stories titled &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.co.uk/arts-entertainment/books/book-review-meeting-god-down-the-pub-the-acid-house-irvine-welsh-cape-pounds-999-1370403.html&#34;&gt;Acid House&lt;/a&gt; by Irvine Welsh. I do not expect to do justice to the arguments in the books (read a real book review if you want that), I&amp;rsquo;m just sharing the lessons I learned from them as a little exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superforecasting is a persuasive essay by a well known academic, Dr Philip Tetlock, on how hard it is to make good decisions. The first half sets the ground by arguing that most &amp;ldquo;expert&amp;rdquo; predictions are either wrong or too vague to assess. There is an entire cottage industry of pundits and hacks built upon the fact that human beings crave certainty and simple narratives in an increasingly uncertain world. Unlike the authors, I don’t think this industry will ever disappear: we’ve still got horoscopes in the internet age. Humans are attracted to anecdotal evidence like we are to junk food:  it is appealing for evolutionary reasons, even if we know it shouldn’t be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://smbc-comics.com/comics/20110626.gif&#34; alt=&#34;a fun comic&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Tetlock then elaborates on decades of highly-interesting research on how to make more accurate predictions. I was surprised that this research was funded by the US intelligence community, which is a professional formation of experts the author has convincingly shown to be more-or-less useless. As an illustration, the book shares a scary anecdote from the days of the Cuban Missile Crisis, when security analysts were asked to judge the likelihood of a highly important outcome. They eventually agreed on writing a memo to the president which said the outcome was “probable”. Later, an outsider asked each analyst how they thought the word “probable” should be interpreted in terms of probability. Answers ranged from 0.3 (it is less likely to happen than not to happen) to 0.7 (it is more likely to happen than not to). We have no idea how Kennedy eventually interpreted it, but luckily we avoided nuclear annihilation. The book argues that forecasting as a profession is not unlike medicine before the arrival of double blind randomised trials. Lots of bloodletting, superstition and occasionally getting lucky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can we make more accurate predictions? The answer is unsurprising: through hard work. More specifically, it requires a painstaking research methodology coupled with an appropriate amount of numeracy. For instance, to determine the probability that Obama will successfully nominate a Supreme court judge now that Justice Scalia is dead, one would first examine potential outcomes (Obama nominates and accepted, Obama doesn&amp;rsquo;t nominate, Obama nominates and isn&amp;rsquo;t accepted), estimate the probability of each based on the base rate (how many nominee&amp;rsquo;s get rejected out of all nominees) and adjust it based on new information. Once a prediction is made, one has to re-evaluate assumptions, auditing errors for both accurate and inaccurate predictions, checking up whether hypotheses are plausible in hindsight. This is very hard. How do you select the appropriate base rate? Is it all presidential nominees? Is it all presidential supreme court nominees? Or perhaps all presidential supreme court nominees nominated by presidents in their last year in office? This is of course a lot more boring than the experts you hear on television.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Importantly, even if something judged as likely to happen does not happen (or vice versa) it does not mean that the judgement was wrong. It’s unlikely you will win the lottery, yet someone has to win. The benefit of hindsight can lead us to make mistaken evaluations, Superforecasters need to learn to avoid them. Tolstoy playfully caricatured this tendency in War and Peace:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The profoundest and most excellent dispositions and orders seem very bad, and every learned militarist criticizes them with looks of importance, when they relate to a battle that has been lost, and the very worst dispositions and orders seem very good, and serious people fill whole volumes to demonstrate their merits, when they relate to a battle that has been won.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, the methods offered by Dr Tetlock are not a panacea, which makes me instinctively less skeptical of his claims. The author admits that some things remain outright impossible: nobody is going to predict the outcome of the 2024 US presidential elections, but Nate Silver and his buddies might be able to tell us that this year’s most likely &lt;a href=&#34;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/donald-trump-is-really-unpopular-with-general-election-voters/&#34;&gt;won&amp;rsquo;t be Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Thiel is somewhat unimpressed by Mr Silver’s efforts in his book (more specifically, of society’s amazement with them), suggesting that the strenuous effort invested in predicting outcomes would be much better invested in trying to influence them. While Tetlock emphasises incremental improvements and careful calibration, Thiel believes true innovation comes from creating something entirely new, hence the title “From Zero to One”. Mr Thiel seems to believe that reality can be altered through the laborious efforts of clever and hardworking individuals, which is the sort of thing a billionaire funding libertarian &lt;a href=&#34;http://theweek.com/articles/482427/libertarian-island-billionaires-utopia&#34;&gt;autonomous communities in international waters&lt;/a&gt; would say. I’m less convinced of the objective truth of his assessment than of its usefulness as a personal philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I seem to come across this sort of Orwellian “doublethink” phenomenon almost always when reading about successful individuals (termed the “reality distortion field” in the Steve Jobs’ biography): the ability to hold an unshakable, far-sighted conviction whilst staying sufficiently grounded in the reality to be able to alter it. What is remarkable is that this phenomenon holds for all sorts of realms, over a wide range of time spans. Max Weber calls it a balance between the “Ethics of Moral Conviction” and the “Ethics of Responsibility”, in &lt;em&gt;Politics as a Vocation&lt;/em&gt;. Regardless whether he is right or wrong, Mr Thiel has undoubtedly done well for himself, perhaps precisely because he is wrong in the right way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://s3-ec.buzzfed.com/static/2014-03/enhanced/webdr05/26/14/enhanced-2984-1395857038-18.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;funny chart&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That Mr Thiel, a serious capitalist, promotes &amp;ldquo;organic&amp;rdquo; monopolies is quite interesting. He believes that competition necessarily eats away at profits, and advises people to work on something that is ten times better, quicker or cheaper than what competitors are doing. In his ideal world, there are no resources wasted with airlines competing against each other, because some space hyper-loop company does transportation so much better than everyone else. According to Thiel’s recipe, you should establish a small monopoly through incredible innovation and aim to scale it, not unlike how Amazon started as an online bookstore and now is building an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.esquire.com/news-politics/news/a26138/amazon-drones/&#34;&gt;army of drones&lt;/a&gt;. It is clear he has Silicon Valley giants in mind, such as Facebook and Google, which hold a meritocratically obtained indisputable monopolies. However, while Facebook is the social network and Google is the search engine, aren’t they competing for the same clients in the online advertising industry? Isn’t scaling a small monopoly just another way to say incremental innovation? How was Facebook 10x better than MySpace? Had Mr Walton followed Thiel’s advice, would he have founded Walmart?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most valuable piece of advice I gleamed from both Thiel and Superforecasting was to appreciate the importance of a well-polished and deliberative methodology, and not to get disappointed by being wrong. This brings me to George Soros’ biography. This book has little in terms specifics on his investments, other than that George Soros can even make money selling unreadable books (the author doesn’t quite say it, but it is clear he thinks they are incomprehensible). However, Soros’ investment methodology includes elements that both Thiel and Tetlock would agree with: hypothesis testing, seeking out mistakes in thinking and going all in when necessary. As Soros said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not whether you&amp;rsquo;re right or wrong, but how much money you make when you&amp;rsquo;re right and how much you lose when you&amp;rsquo;re wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a lot more engaging Soros’ passion and influence on global politics through his philanthropy. Yet even here, the painful complexities of forecasting and subsequent decision-making are apparent. Two out of three of Hungary’s most important public servants, PM Orban and Speaker Kover received scholarships by Mr Soros’s Open Society Foundations when they were young. They are now both considered to be strongly anti-liberal and hostile to Soros. Is funding people who disagree with you consistent with the goals of Soros’ Open Society? Was
Mr Soros wrong in funding them, or would saying so merely be making the same argument Tolstoy ridicules?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the subject of being wrong, there are few people for whom it is more expensive to be very wrong than the Chairman of the Federal Reserve. Ben Bernanke, former Chairman of the Fed (2006-2014), published a book last year mostly about how he was right. I particularly liked Bernanke&amp;rsquo;s style, his writing exudes a calm and confidence of a central banker, almost (but not quite) to the point of making the hectic days of the crisis sound boring. As expected, he makes convincing arguments for his policies of bailouts and quantitative easing, making the interesting parallel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You have a neighbor, who smokes in bed&amp;hellip; . Suppose he sets fire to his house, you might say to yourself &amp;hellip; ‘I’m not gonna call the fire department. Let his house burn down. It’s fine with me.’ But then, of course, what if your house is made of wood? And it’s right next door to his house? What if the whole town is made of wood?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not well versed enough in economics to assess the merits and nuances of his argument, what I can assess is that many of the predictions which stem from these arguments don’t stack up to Superforecasting’s verifiability requirements: it is nearly impossible to know whether he was right or wrong. Partly this is because you cannot rewind time and try to do something different to see what happens but also because of their vagueness. For instance, notable critics of QE said it would cause runaway inflation in the US. It hasn’t happened yet, does that mean they were wrong? I am sure that if it happens within the next few years they’ll say “I told you so”, but even then we won’t know for certain. With a healthy dose of self-criticism, Bernanke quips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Economists are criticized for not being able to predict the future, but, because the data are incomplete and subject to revision, we cannot even be sure what happened in the recent past.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is more interesting from my perspective is the role of the central banker in times of a panic. I can’t help but think it is very much like the role of a well-intentioned host in a drug party, reassuring people curled up in the corner on a LSD bad trip, giving some coke to help “sober up” to the drunk guys throwing up on the floor and telling the stoners trying to eat 10 liters of ice cream that it probably isn’t a good idea. The only difficulty is that the host isn’t quite sober himself, and any “treatment” he puts on the table is probably also going to be taken by someone who really shouldn’t. Meanwhile, his abusive parents are about to come home drunk from their own party, and they&amp;rsquo;re going to be pissed off when they find out they have to pay for this mess. This allegory probably arises from the fact that I read Acid House concurrently. If you ever suffer from stressful days and sleep-less nights, as Bernanke did between 2007 and 2008, short stories of junkies will make you appreciate that there are many people who have it much worse than you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What our druggie analogy fails to capture is that the key element is that bubbles and panics develop not because the underlying fundamentals (whether people stop paying their morgages) shift radically, but because other what people think other people think. So? Well I’ll go out on a limb and make a prediction that it is more likely than not that a new crisis will emerge in the next two years. Of course, this prediction isn’t up to Superforcasting standards, it is simply based on the fact that they tend to happen every decade or so and I am reading more and more uneasy news. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave more analytical financial predictions to the Soros types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By the way, the comics are from &lt;a href=&#34;http://smbc-comics.com/&#34;&gt;SMBC.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read in 2015</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/12/27/what-i-read-in-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/12/27/what-i-read-in-2015/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I bought my Kindle slightly over a year ago, and since it has accompanied me everywhere I&amp;rsquo;ve been.
It has provided me with entertainment on long journeys and education in subjects where I had none. I would like to share some of my favourite quotes. I have sorted them based on when I started reading them, with some slight editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;december-2014&#34;&gt;December (2014)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-prince-niccolò-machiavelli&#34;&gt;﻿The Prince (Niccolò Machiavelli)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, pretexts for taking away the property are never wanting; for he who has once begun to live by robbery will always find pretexts for seizing what belongs to others; but reasons for taking life, on the contrary, are more difficult to find and sooner lapse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two men working differently bring about the same effect, and of two working similarly, one attains his object and the other does not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I consider that it is better to be adventurous than cautious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people-dale-carnegie&#34;&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People (Dale Carnegie)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of our so- called reasoning consists in finding arguments for going on believing as we already do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin Luther King was asked how, as a pacifist, he could be an admirer of Air Force General Daniel &amp;ldquo;Chappie&amp;rdquo; James, then the nation&amp;rsquo;s highest-ranking black officer. Dr. King replied, &amp;ldquo;I judge people by their own principles - not by my own.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;J. Pierpont Morgan observed, in one of his analytical interludes, that a person usually has two reasons for doing a thing: one that sounds good and a real one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a hundred years before Christ was born a famous old Roman poet, Publilius Syrus, remarked; &amp;ldquo;We are interested in others when they are interested in us.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Talk to people about themselves,&amp;rdquo; said Disraeli, one of the shrewdest men who ever ruled the British Empire. &amp;ldquo;Talk to people about themselves and they will listen for hours .&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-autobiography-of-benjamin-franklin-benjamin-franklin&#34;&gt;The Autobiography of Benjamin Franklin (Benjamin Franklin)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people dislike vanity in others, whatever share they have of it themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This flattered my vanity; but my father discouraged me by ridiculing my performances, and telling me verse-makers were generally beggars. So I escaped being a poet, most probably a very bad one; but as prose writing had been of great use to me in the course of my life, and was a principal means of my advancement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[On getting into arguments] Persons of good sense, I have since observed, seldom fall into it, except lawyers, university men, and men of all sorts that have been bred at Edinborough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men should be taught as if you taught them not, And things unknown propos&amp;rsquo;d as things forgot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A man being sometimes more generous when he has but a little money than when he has plenty, perhaps thro&amp;rsquo; fear of being thought to have but little. &amp;ldquo;He that has once done you a kindness will be more ready to do you another, than he whom you yourself have obliged.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to secure my credit and character as a tradesman, I took care not only to be in reality industrious and frugal, but to avoid all appearances to the contrary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;theodore-roosevelt-an-autobiography-roosevelt-theodore&#34;&gt;Theodore Roosevelt; an Autobiography (Roosevelt, Theodore)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thoroughly enjoyed Harvard, and I am sure it did me good, but only in the general effect, for there was very little in my actual studies which helped me in after life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He says that at the outset almost every man is frightened when he goes into action, but that the course to follow is for the man to keep such a grip on himself that he can act just as if he was not frightened. After this is kept up long enough it changes from pretense to reality, and the man does in very fact become fearless by sheer dint of practicing fearlessness when he does not feel it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not then believe, and I do not now believe, that any man should ever attempt to make politics his only career. It is a dreadful misfortune for a man to grow to feel that his whole livelihood and whole happiness depend upon his staying in office. Such a feeling prevents him from being of real service to the people while in office, and always puts him under the heaviest strain of pressure to barter his convictions for the sake of holding office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went around there often enough to have the men get accustomed to me and to have me get accustomed to them, so that we began to speak the same language, and so that each could begin to live down in the other&amp;rsquo;s mind what Bret Harte has called &amp;ldquo;the defective moral quality of being a stranger.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not often that a man can make opportunities for himself. But he can put himself in such shape that when or if the opportunities come he is ready to take advantage of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one of us cares permanently to have some one else conscientiously striving to do him good; what we want is to work with that some one else for the good of both of us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any man who has met with success, if he will be frank with himself, must admit that there has been a big element of fortune in the success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let him remember, by the way, that the unforgivable crime is soft hitting. Do not hit at all if it can be avoided; but never hit softly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made no promise which we could not and did not keep. We made no threat which we did not carry out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nine-tenths of wisdom is to be wise in time, and at the right time;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;january&#34;&gt;January&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;sam-walton-made-in-america-sam-walton&#34;&gt;Sam Walton Made in America (Sam Walton)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a long time ago that exercising your ego in public is definitely not the way to build an effective organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It never occurred to me that I might lose; to me, it was almost as if I had a right to win. Thinking like that often seems to turn into sort of a self-fulfilling prophecy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I realize the simple truth: I got into retailing because I was tired and I wanted a real job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way we tried hard to make up for our lack of experience and sophistication was to spend as much time as we could checking out the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;andrew-carnegie-david-nasaw&#34;&gt;Andrew Carnegie (David Nasaw)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a talent for cloaking self-interest in larger humanitarian concerns, he made a premature case for free public libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carnegie had all his life found a way to attach himself to older people who could be of use to him—and he to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To raise money for roads not yet built and probably not really needed, Carnegie and Scott trafficked in what Richard White refers to as “the utilitarian fictions of capitalism.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WHEN A.B. FARQUHAR, a Pennsylvania businessman, mentioned to Carnegie that he was always sure to be in his office by “seven in the morning,” Carnegie remarked laughingly: “‘You must be a lazy man if it takes you ten hours to do a day’s work.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-picture-of-dorian-gray-oscar-wilde&#34;&gt;The Picture of Dorian Gray (Oscar Wilde)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highest as the lowest form of criticism is a mode of autobiography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is silly of you, for there is only one thing in the world worse than being talked about, and that is not being talked about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Always! That is a dreadful word. It makes me shudder when I hear it. Women are so fond of using it. They spoil every romance by trying to make it last for ever. It is a meaningless word, too. The only difference between a caprice and a lifelong passion is that the caprice lasts a little longer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What a fuss people make about fidelity!&amp;rdquo; exclaimed Lord Henry. &amp;ldquo;Why, even in love it is purely a question for physiology. It has nothing to do with our own will. Young men want to be faithful, and are not; old men want to be faithless, and cannot: that is all one can say.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Humph! tell your Aunt Agatha, Harry, not to bother me any more with her charity appeals. I am sick of them. Why, the good woman thinks that I have nothing to do but to write cheques for her silly fads.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;All right, Uncle George, I&amp;rsquo;ll tell her, but it won&amp;rsquo;t have any effect. Philanthropic people lose all sense of humanity. It is their distinguishing characteristic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Never marry a woman with straw-coloured hair, Dorian,&amp;rdquo; he said after a few puffs. &amp;ldquo;Why, Harry?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Because they are so sentimental.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;But I like sentimental people.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Never marry at all, Dorian. Men marry because they are tired; women, because they are curious: both are disappointed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When one is in love, one always begins by deceiving one&amp;rsquo;s self, and one always ends by deceiving others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever a man does a thoroughly stupid thing, it is always from the noblest motives.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;one of those middle-aged mediocrities so common in London clubs who have no enemies, but are thoroughly disliked by their friends;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What nonsense people talk about happy marriages!&amp;rdquo; exclaimed Lord Henry. &amp;ldquo;A man can be happy with any woman, as long as he does not love her.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;february&#34;&gt;February&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;war-and-peace-graf-leo-tolstoy&#34;&gt;War and Peace (graf Leo Tolstoy)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He spoke with such self-confidence that his hearers could not be sure whether what he said was very witty or very stupid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even in the best, most friendly and simplest relations of life, praise and commendation are essential, just as grease is necessary to wheels that they may run smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t love people so much for the good they have done us, as for the good we have done them.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t be angry with me for exercising an old woman&amp;rsquo;s privilege.&amp;rdquo; She paused, as women always do, expecting something after they have mentioned their age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was so plain that neither of them could think of her as a rival, so they began dressing her with perfect sincerity, and with the naive and firm conviction women have that dress can make a face pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helene Bezukhova&amp;rsquo;s reputation as a lovely and clever woman became so firmly established that she could say the emptiest and stupidest things and everybody would go into raptures over every word of hers and look for a profound meaning in it of which she herself had no conception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anatole, with the partiality dull-witted people have for any conclusion they have reached by their own reasoning, repeated the argument he had already put to Dolokhov a hundred times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The members of this party, chiefly civilians and to whom Arakcheev belonged, thought and said what men who have no convictions but wish to seem to have some generally say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pfuel was one of those hopelessly and immutably self-confident men, self-confident to the point of martyrdom as only Germans are, because only Germans are self-confident on the basis of an abstract notion—science, that is, the supposed knowledge of absolute truth. A Frenchman is self-assured because he regards himself personally, both in mind and body, as irresistibly attractive to men and women. An Englishman is self-assured, as being a citizen of the best-organized state in the world, and therefore as an Englishman always knows what he should do and knows that all he does as an Englishman is undoubtedly correct. An Italian is self-assured because he is excitable and easily forgets himself and other people. A Russian is self-assured just because he knows nothing and does not want to know anything, since he does not believe that anything can be known. The German&amp;rsquo;s self-assurance is worst of all, stronger and more repulsive than any other, because he imagines that he knows the truth—science—which he himself has invented but which is for him the absolute truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only does a good army commander not need any special qualities, on the contrary he needs the absence of the highest and best human attributes—love, poetry, tenderness, and philosophic inquiring doubt. He should be limited, firmly convinced that what he is doing is very important (otherwise he will not have sufficient patience), and only then will he be a brave leader. God forbid that he should be humane, should love, or pity, or think of what is just and unjust. It is understandable that a theory of their &amp;lsquo;genius&amp;rsquo; was invented for them long ago because they have power!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The profoundest and most excellent dispositions and orders seem very bad, and every learned militarist criticizes them with looks of importance, when they relate to a battle that has been lost, and the very worst dispositions and orders seem very good, and serious people fill whole volumes to demonstrate their merits, when they relate to a battle that has been won.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as it always happens in contests of cunning that a stupid person gets the better of cleverer ones,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;losing-my-virginity-how-i-survived-had-fun-and-made-a-fortune-doing-business-my-way-richard-branson&#34;&gt;Losing My Virginity: How I Survived, Had Fun, and Made a Fortune Doing Business My Way (Richard Branson)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granny was 99 when she died. Shortly before that, she had written to me to say that the previous ten years had been the best of her life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he walked out of the meeting, he turned to one of his companions and made a comment which was picked up on the intercom and broadcast all over the office. He said, ‘I’ll be in my grave before that fucker gets his logo on my trains.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-history-of-the-peloponnesian-war-thucydides&#34;&gt;The History of the Peloponnesian War (Thucydides)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men&amp;rsquo;s indignation, it seems, is more excited by legal wrong than by violent wrong; the first looks like being cheated by an equal, the second like being compelled by a superior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am more afraid of our own blunders than of the enemy&amp;rsquo;s devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zeal is always at its height at the commencement of an undertaking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that great good fortune coming suddenly and unexpectedly tends to make a people insolent;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this contest the blunter wits were most successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;may&#34;&gt;May&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;collected-essays-orwell-george-1903-1950&#34;&gt;Collected Essays (Orwell, George, 1903-1950)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is curious, but till that moment I had never realized what it means to destroy a healthy, conscious man. When I saw the prisoner step aside to avoid the puddle, I saw the mystery, the unspeakable wrongness, of cutting a life short when it is in full tide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doubtless any horoscope seems ‘true’ if it tells you that you are highly attractive to the opposite sex and your worst fault is generosity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Moulmein, in lower Burma, I was hated by large numbers of people — the only time in my life that I have been important enough for this to happen to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But traditions are not killed by facts, and the tradition of Northern’ grit’ lingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gazelles are almost the only animals that look good to eat when they are still alive, in fact, one can hardly look at their hindquarters without thinking of mint sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally I believe that most people are influenced far more than they would care to admit by novels, serial stories, films and so forth, and that from this point of view the worst books are often the most important, because they are usually the ones that are read earliest in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All writers are vain, selfish, and lazy, and at the very bottom of their motives there lies a mystery. Writing a book is a horrible, exhausting struggle, like a long bout of some painful illness. One would never undertake such a thing if one were not driven on by some demon whom one can neither resist nor understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are people who are convinced of the wickedness both of armies and of police forces, but who are nevertheless much more intolerant and inquisitorial in outlook than the normal person who believes that it is necessary to use violence in certain circumstances. They will not say to somebody else, “Do this, that and the other or you will go to prison”, but they will, if they can, get inside his brain and dictate his thoughts for him in the minutest particulars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;journey-to-the-west-wu-cheng-en&#34;&gt;Journey to the West (Wu Cheng-en)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘The magistrate may be wrong and the sergeant may be wrong, but the man who comes to get you is never wrong.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hundred years flow by like water; A lifetime’s career is no more than a bubble, The face that yesterday was the color of peach-blossom Today is edged with snow. When the white ants’ line of battle collapses, all is illusion; “Repent, repent,” is the cuckoo’s urgent call. He who does good in secret can always prolong his life; Heaven looks after the one who asks no pity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How true it is that blessings never come in pairs and troubles never come singly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sex is a sword that wounds the body; Whoever lusts for it will suffer. A pretty girl of sixteen Is far more dangerous than a yaksha demon. There is only one Origin, And there are no extra profits to staff in the sack. Better store all your capital away, Guard it well, and don’t squander it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clear wine makes the cheeks go red; Gold turns everybody’s head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How true it is that however good you are at something there’s always somebody better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘A man with no woman is risking his wealth; a woman with no husband is risking her health.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cat that’s won a fight is more pleased with himself than a tiger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How true it is that the night is long in loneliness and short in pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“However high a mountain is it can’t possibly join up with the sky.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Make a move and your fortune’s one third made.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s an old saying that there’s nothing like liquor for ending a life,” Monkey replied, “and another that there’s nothing like liquor for solving any problem. Liquor’s very useful stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ve no more chance of getting away from here than of covering up a fart with your hands. Where do you think you’re going?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Trust not the straightest of the straight; beware of the inhuman human.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Soft words will get you anywhere on earth; act rough and you won’t move a single step,”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is in all of our interests. We may not be much use, but even a fart can strengthen a breeze.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘The mountain may be in view, but your horse will collapse before you get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;june&#34;&gt;June&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;burmese-days-orwell-george-1903-1950&#34;&gt;Burmese Days (Orwell, George, 1903-1950)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only he would always talk about shooting, instead of about books and Art and that mucky poetry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was her first introduction to the fact that some men are capable of making love to their nieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘nasty, brutish, and in shorts’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An earthquake is such fun when it is over. It is so exhilarating to reflect that you are not, as you well might be, lying dead under a heap of ruins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once he had loved Elizabeth spiritually, sentimentally indeed, desiring her sympathy more than her caresses; now, when he had lost her, he was tormented by the basest physical longing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;july&#34;&gt;July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-gambler-fyodor-dostoyevsky&#34;&gt;The Gambler (Fyodor Dostoyevsky)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Invite a man to your table, and soon he will place his feet upon it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-importance-of-being-earnest-a-trivial-comedy-for-serious-people-oscar-wilde&#34;&gt;The Importance of Being Earnest: A Trivial Comedy for Serious People (Oscar Wilde)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have only been married once.  That was in consequence of a misunderstanding between myself and a young person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My duty as a gentleman has never interfered with my pleasures in the smallest degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;august&#34;&gt;August&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-brothers-karamazov-fyodor-dostoyevsky&#34;&gt;The Brothers Karamazov (Fyodor Dostoyevsky)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a general rule, people, even the wicked, are much more naïve and simple-hearted than we suppose. And we ourselves are, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had a high opinion of his own insight, a weakness excusable in him as he was fifty, an age at which a clever man of the world of established position can hardly help taking himself rather seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man who lies to himself and listens to his own lie comes to such a pass that he cannot distinguish the truth within him, or around him, and so loses all respect for himself and for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schoolboys are a merciless race, individually they are angels, but together, especially in schools, they are often merciless. Their teasing has stirred up a gallant spirit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t despise me for [pg 225] that, sir, in Russia men who drink are the best. The best men amongst us are the greatest drunkards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;september&#34;&gt;September&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-better-angels-of-our-nature-why-violence-has-declined-steven-pinker&#34;&gt;The Better Angels of Our Nature: Why Violence Has Declined (Steven Pinker)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the novelist Robert Howard put it, “Civilized men are more discourteous than savages because they know they can be impolite without having their skulls split.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who can make you believe absurdities can make you commit atrocities. —Voltaire&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Mario Puzo’s novel The Godfather, Vito Corleone is credited with the principle “Accidents don’t happen to people who take accidents as a personal insult.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The American implementation had a flaw that is best captured in the actor Ice-T’s impression of Thomas Jefferson reviewing a draft of the Constitution: “Let’s see: freedom of speech; freedom of religion; freedom of the press; you can own niggers &amp;hellip; Looks good to me!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genghis Khan, offered this reflection on the pleasures of life: “The greatest joy a man can know is to conquer his enemies and drive them before him. To ride their horses and take away their possessions. To see the faces of those who were dear to them bedewed with tears, and to clasp their wives and daughters in his arms.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Hume observed, “The humour of blaming the present, and admiring the past, is strongly rooted in human nature, and has an influence even on persons endowed with the profoundest judgment and most extensive learning.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mothers with postpartum depression often feel emotionally detached from their newborns and may harbor intrusive thoughts of harming them. Mild depression, psychologists have found, often gives people a more accurate appraisal of their life prospects than the rose-tinted view we normally enjoy. The typical rumination of a depressed new mother—how will I cope with this burden?—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George Orwell with an earlier formulation of the idea: “The secret of rulership is to combine a belief in one’s own infallibility with a power to learn from past mistakes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world has far too much morality. If you added up all the homicides committed in pursuit of self-help justice, the casualties of religious and revolutionary wars, the people executed for victimless crimes and misdemeanors, and the targets of ideological genocides, they would surely outnumber the fatalities from amoral predation and conquest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;october-november-december&#34;&gt;October, November, December&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;love-in-the-time-of-the-cholera-gabriel-garcia-marquez&#34;&gt;Love in the Time of the Cholera(Gabriel Garcia Marquez)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All my quotes are in Spanish, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/work/quotes/3285349-el-amor-en-los-tiempos-del-c-lera&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; are a few great ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>