<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance on Boaz Sobrado&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>http://boazsobrado.com/categories/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on Boaz Sobrado&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 17:58:21 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://boazsobrado.com/categories/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Cuba Is Primed for Bitcoin Adoption</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2020/12/11/why-cuba-is-primed-for-bitcoin-adoption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 17:58:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2020/12/11/why-cuba-is-primed-for-bitcoin-adoption/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally published as an Op-Ed on Decrypt
Cuba is having one of its worst years in recent memory&amp;mdash;but, as a consequence, a perfect storm is brewing on the island nation with regard to Bitcoin adoption.
Cubans live under a high level of financial censorship, as well as rampant inflation. Meanwhile, their access to foreign currencies has been heavily curtailed this year due to COVID and US sanctions. This has increased the appeal of cryptocurrencies, many of which act as censorship-resistant stores of value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DeFi Still Needs a Silk Road Moment</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2020/10/30/defi-still-needs-a-silk-road-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 17:58:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2020/10/30/defi-still-needs-a-silk-road-moment/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally published as an Op-Ed on CoinDesk
Mainstream criminal adoption would prove that decentralized finance (DeFi) is building tools with real utility, because if there&amp;rsquo;s any one group that is both underserved in their access to sophisticated financial products and willing to pay huge premiums to acquire them, it&amp;rsquo;s criminals. The Silk Road was launched in February of 2011 and quickly became the first example of Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s product-market fit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>