<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Boaz Sobrado&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>http://boazsobrado.com/categories/politics/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Boaz Sobrado&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://boazsobrado.com/categories/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump and Zuckerberg&#39;s Matrix</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/02/29/donald-trump-and-zuckerbergs-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/02/29/donald-trump-and-zuckerbergs-matrix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prediction markets have the Republican nomination for President of the USA going to billionaire reality TV host and megalomaniac Donald Trump. On the other side of the aisle, self-described socialist Sanders is making Hillary Clinton’s campaign sweat. This isn’t “politics as usual” for anyone except the writers of The Simpsons.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.snopes.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/SimpsonsTrumpEpisode2000.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34; /&gt;
According to the party decides theory (or at least my interpretation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://fivethirtyeight.com/tag/the-party-decides/&#34;&gt;Nate Silver’s interpretation&lt;/a&gt;) the party, as a loose coalition of opinion forming individuals, can heavily weigh in on who gets nominated. Yet they took so long to settle on Rubio that Trump is now the likeliest candidate. Perhaps this is a sign of the GOP’s weakness, or perhaps they hate Cruz more than they hate Trump. These are all strong arguments that have been well &lt;a href=&#34;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/dont-assume-conservatives-will-rally-behind-trump/&#34;&gt;argued elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;, but I would like to present an alternative one: the party just isn’t as effective at forming opinions as it used to be, because social media has created a pervasive platform for radicalisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The downfall of traditional media has been written about extensively. And in this election more than ever, Facebook is playing a key role across a wide range of demographic groups. The majority of Americans use Facebook as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.journalism.org/2015/07/14/the-evolving-role-of-news-on-twitter-and-facebook/&#34;&gt;news source&lt;/a&gt;. The editor of your Facebook Newsfeed is one personally tailored just for you, and this editor carefully selects articles based on what you engage with. For the most part, the news it selects is news you agree with. This plays to well-known psychological biases and Facebook has hundreds of clever people working on algorithms to cater to them. This isn’t surprising in itself: if the algorithms weren’t doing the filtering, &lt;a href=&#34;http://distractify.com/humor/2015/12/10/mustafa-delete-trump-friends&#34;&gt;you would yourself&lt;/a&gt;. In a sense, not much has changed: the majority of left wing voters don’t read right wing newspapers, and viceversa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference is the pervasiveness and social element in social media. The dynamics of Facebook, with its selective Newsfeed algorithms and the fact that people with radical beliefs &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.weforum.org/agenda/2016/01/q-a-walter-quattrociocchi-digital-wildfires?utm_content=buffer32041&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=facebook.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&#34;&gt;like and share more content&lt;/a&gt;, produce echo chambers, where people share the same ideas and the same arguments. Again, echo chambers themselves are not new phenomena, just look at Fox News (or your least favourite newspaper). What is new however, is that many more people are being exposed to them for much longer. Millions of individuals start their days looking at Facebook and finish their day likewise. Most left-wing readers do not read right-wing newspapers, but only radicals read party propaganda all day, every day.  I hypothesize that Facebook’s Newsfeed makes it is likelier you start thinking echo chamber views are actually widespread. If an acquaintance keeps sharing information that shows vaccines are a global conspiracy, you’re more likely to express any skepticism regarding vaccines than if you think it is unacceptable to do so. Effectively, the internet helps marginalised communities by helping people find likeminded individuals and giving them a platform to express their views. A gay boy in the Bible belt will find it easier to find similar people and talk about his experiences. So will eugenicists, flat-earth believers and paedophiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook, in conjunction with your opinionated buddies, can make the unthinkable thinkable by removing stigma associated with certain opinions (or viceversa). If you often see articles in your newsfeed about “rape-culture” you’ll have the intuition that it is one of the biggest concerns people have. You might be shocked and perhaps offended when you overhear a casual misogynistic comment because for you it’s a big deal and you’ve read, commented and liked loads of articles on the objectification on women and related topics. It’s a big transgression for you, but for many people, it just isn’t such a big deal. Similarly, people who hate immigrants may be astounded by the Willkommenskultur of others. If we believe in an objective reality, it only natural that we assume that others have roughly the same sources of information that we do. Facebook may be further inflating our already misguided estimates of the extent to which others agree with us. The less diverse our social network, the greater the danger our views will shift considerably from the majority’s without us even noticing. I know educated people who sincerely believe Sanders will be nominated.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.smbc-comics.com/comics/20111215.gif&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So is Facebook responsible for the rise of radicals? A convincing counterargument is that more than anything it seems like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/walter-shapiro-donald-trump-media-coverage_us_56982b8ce4b0ce496423f627&#34;&gt;traditional media is going crazy for Trump.&lt;/a&gt; Nonetheless, it is an empirically testable hypothesis: radical candidates should be more popular amongst people who use Facebook as a primary news source. I was not able to find any data where I could confirm or deny this hypothesis. Yet, regardless of whether it is wrong or not (I suspect the answer is “it depends”, but even a couple of percentage points of influence can write history), it still raises three important questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first question is related to agency: who supervises the editor robots? If you read an inflammatory article or see a controversial TV show you can easily find out who the editor is and who owns the channel. It remains without saying that the reason you saw it is because you chose to flick on that particular channel or buy that particular newspaper. If I read an article in the Economist, it is because the author wrote it, the editor accepted it and I went and bought the magazine. In theory, journalists have a professional code of conduct. Newsfeed algorithms do not. Moreover, the fact that they are algorithms makes it even more difficult to assess the question of responsibility, because they are a blackbox nobody really understands: data went in, results came out. They have no professional responsibility to show you a balanced view on the world and it’s partly your fault for watching too many cat videos. It’s not implausible to consider that systemic biases in how they work may even influence elections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, we should ever more aware that he who controls our perception of reality controls reality. Zuckerberg, as a good student of psychology, no doubt knows this. He is in fact very excited about how perception can be manipulated with gadgets such as the Occulus Rift (as I am). I have no reason to think his intentions are evil, and I was lucky to have a glimpse of his desk in Facebook&amp;rsquo;s HQ, and I didn’t see any world conquest plans. But we should be well aware of Lord Acton’s famous quip about absolute power. I used to think Chinese banning Facebook as a dangerous American weapon was ludicrous. After Snowden’s revelations, I am not so sure.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://scontent-mia1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpl1/v/t1.0-9/12063844_10102665120179591_3471165635858509622_n.jpg?oh=8887d38ca26b339f74cef594f82d6bce&amp;amp;oe=575C754B&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34; /&gt;
Third, what can we do to prevent ourselves from being uncannily influenced by our biases of reality? My previous post reviewing Superforecasters gives a &lt;a href=&#34;http://boazsobrado.com/blog/book_review_Boaz_1/&#34;&gt;few hints&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Migrant Crisis and Demography</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/11/05/the-migrant-crisis-and-demography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/11/05/the-migrant-crisis-and-demography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In September, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/world/2015/sep/16/hungarian-riot-police-use-water-cannon-against-refugees&#34;&gt;images&lt;/a&gt;
of anti-riot police in a standoff with desperate migrants were shown on television, inspiring many people to volunteer and even more people to chatter about the situation.
Yet the problem with our handling of crises is that we often wait for one to happen before doing anything (even just notice something is amiss).
Humans are vulnerable to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychophysics&#34;&gt;overlooking gradual phenomena&lt;/a&gt;
 with no easily distinguishable onset.
There is an ongoing global demographic transition and it will influence most shifts in the next 25 years, be it in politics, business or international relations.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://static1.squarespace.com/static/5408e9b3e4b0e5142540c5d3/t/55ef18a9e4b0845c040109e2/1441732779464/&#34; alt=&#34;Demographic onion&#34; title=&#34;An onion&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The global population pyramid is turning into what demographers call an &lt;a href=&#34;http://esa.un.org/unpd/wpp/publications/files/key_findings_wpp_2015.pdf&#34;&gt;onion&lt;/a&gt;.
While population growth continues and the global population is predicted to reach 9.7 billion by 2050, growth rates are slowing and there is a vast divergence between geographic regions.
For instance, half the population growth between now and 2050 is expected to occur in Africa whereas Europe’s population is expected to decrease.
Moreover, increasing longevity and decreasing fertility mean that the population aged over 60 is fastest growing (expected to go from 0.9 billion to 2.1 billion by 2050).
Since the dawn of civilisation the global population has always been young and growing. This is no longer the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To feed the burgeoning developing world food production must increase until 2095 when fertility levels converge to replacement level.
A failure to do so could lead to unprecedented famines. In the developed world political pressures raised by the care of the elderly will step into the limelight.
By 2050 the number of workers per retiree will drop to below 2 in 35 (mostly European) countries.
It is not difficult to concieve how this may lead to animosity within the working force in countries with significant wealth redistribution.
On the other hand, China, traditionally reliant on familial support, faces the risk of millions of elders falling outside safety nets.
Moreover, the economic and demographic asymmetry between the developed and the developing world will become an increasingly powerful driver of migration, much to the chagrin of politicians like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newser.com/article/b8cb3d73621b410f909328378387196d/the-latest-hungarys-viktor-orban-says-europe-should-not-use-migration-to-boost-population.html&#34;&gt;Viktor Orban&lt;/a&gt;.
Politically, we must be prepared for an inter-generational conflict with a multicultural twist.
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lygsbtd.files.wordpress.com/2012/02/baby-boomer-cartoon-1qzbymy.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Evidence of conflict&#34; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Businesswise, companies are scrambling to provide for the growing population of the developing world to make up for declining consumption in developed world.
More worryingly, consumer behaviour in the developed world is changing beyond what would be expected from demographic changes.
Statistics show young people today are quite unlike young people in the 1970’s: much &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/news/briefing/21606795-todays-young-people-are-held-be-alienated-unhappy-violent-failures-they-are-proving&#34;&gt;less drugs, sex and rock-and-roll&lt;/a&gt; (and cars, disposable income and alcohol).
The businesses of tomorrow must either latch onto the growth of developing countries or to growth areas of the developed world (such as healthcare).
&lt;img src=&#34;http://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/original-size/images/print-edition/20121027_BRC338_0.png&#34; alt=&#34;Well behaved&#34; title=&#34;Alcohol use&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure peace and prosperity we must be prepared to adapt to this new reality.
Above all, leaders must recognise that mass migration, in one way or another, is likely to be inevitable and efforts should be made to soften cultural and intergenerational shocks.
For instance, wealthy aging countries could sponsor schools in young poor states which would act as a funnel for well-educated immigrants with the relevant language skills.
Much more can be learnt from states with experience in immigration (such as the United States). Only then might we avoid the most dramatic images on television today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt; Graphs shamelessly stolen from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/&#34;&gt;The Economist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t fear foreign education</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2012/11/20/dont-fear-foreign-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2012/11/20/dont-fear-foreign-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Startling new data show that emigration out of Hungary is at a 20-year record high and that many more Hungarians have seriously considered leaving Hungary to live, work, or study in another member state of the EU. But instead of speaking ominously about the potentially catastrophic consequences of such emigration trends for Hungary, it is useful to think of this increased mobility as a potentially positive phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geographic mobility is often an indicator of social mobility. Movement allows workers and entrepreneurs to fill market gaps wherever they may be found. In fact, it is estimated that increased mobility in the EU would greatly enhance European competitiveness in comparison to the United States, where citizens have always been willing to move in search of opportunities, and China, where urbanisation has been key to economic growth. Of course, international mobility may be considered qualitatively different than national mobility. Moving from Budapest to Győr (or from California to New York) is different than moving from Hungary to Germany or England. These differences ought not to be overstated, however; we are now part of a pan-European single market (whether we like it or not), and geographic mobility has become a central characteristic of that market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while enterprise is something supported by both the government and the opposition, international mobility has been spoken about in almost exclusively negative terms. Furthermore, keeping people (especially young people) in Hungary seems to be the policy of the government (see the recent Új Nemzedék video). This is shocking. Back in 2001, one of the greatest selling points in the debate about EU membership was that Hungarian citizens would be free to work, study, and live in all of Europe. Yet today, more people seem interested in discouraging exactly that type of mobility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many are leaving in order to seek better opportunities, to gain a better understanding of the world, and to develop as a person. Such reasons for leaving Hungary no doubt cast a light on the negative aspects within the country: an anti-meritocratic, anti-entrepreneurial environment and a negative mentality are just a few of the reasons often cited by those who leave. The government discourages emigration as a way of denying the existence of deep-seated social problems in Hungary. Some social problems, of course, cannot necessarily be fixed by any government program, but must be remedied by the Hungarian people themselves exercising their freedom responsibly and improving their culture person by person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking this into account, mobility should be encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hungarian system of higher education is in desperate need of competition. A small number of cash-strapped universities limit the options for Hungarian undergraduates. Now that the majority of students actually have to pay for higher education in Hungary, they are becoming more aware of what they are paying for. Particularly considering that countries such as Scotland and Denmark offer tuition-free education. The increased mobility of students will force Hungarian universities to compete for their attention, possibly by driving down costs and increasing the quality of education. It is no longer a choice between Corvinus and BME. And no matter how good Hungarian universities become, there will always be outstanding opportunities at colleges and universities in the 27 other EU member states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Hungary’s shortcomings in language education (it has one of the worst rates of foreign language proficiency in the EU) hamper many students’ abilities to seek out education abroad. This is regrettable, since the language skills and cultural interactions that come from studying out of country are central to making the single market work and encouraging entrepreneurial innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why isn’t the government informing students of the incredible opportunities abroad? There are legitimate concerns that the most talented students will stay in their country of study. While other countries, like Denmark, do offer higher wages, they also often offer much higher living costs and not necessarily a higher quality of life than that found in Hungary.  Emigrants often want to come back to Hungary eventually, and many would even be willing to take a pay cut to do so. After all, while Új Nemzedék’s video may not quite have captured it perfectly for all of us, living in Hungary is a fantastic experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hungarian leaders should try harder to organize opportunities for Hungarians abroad, connecting the best talent with Hungarian companies based back in Hungary. Malaysia is already doing this, targeting Malaysian students studying in England and providing them with concrete career opportunities; this might work better than a YouTube video. Or consider the example of Slovenia, where the government pays tuition fees for students studying in EU countries under the condition that they work in Slovenia after graduation. With students in the UK expecting as much as £ 21000 in debt by the time they graduate, they will take any help they can get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobility and emigration should not be categorically suspect. Instead, Hungarians should consider the European Union an extension of the possibilities available to them for education or work. And the government should encourage Hungarians to want to return to their homeland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post appeared originally in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paprikapolitik.com/2012/11/dont-fear-foreign-education/&#34;&gt;Paprika Politik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>