<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coding on Boaz Sobrado&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>http://boazsobrado.com/categories/coding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coding on Boaz Sobrado&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 12:52:58 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://boazsobrado.com/categories/coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Where I was in 2018</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2019/01/13/where-i-was-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 12:52:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2019/01/13/where-i-was-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>I spent a lot of time this year on the road. I started 2018 on a tropical beach in the Phillipines and ended it in Lisbon, with a lot of trips in between. Given that I spent a good part of this year playing around with maps for my thesis, I thought it would be fun to use my Google Location Services data to animate my movement this year. Here is the result:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A smart email &amp; SMS bot on AWS using R</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2018/11/08/a-smart-email--sms-bot-on-aws-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 12:52:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2018/11/08/a-smart-email--sms-bot-on-aws-using-r/</guid>
      <description>I face the following problem: I get a lot of similarly formatted emails that require some sort of action that can in theory be easily automated. For example, I get Woocommerce order notifications that I want to forward selectively to my team via SMS.
It turns out there is no Gmail extension that will help you do that (or at least I didn&amp;rsquo;t find anything like it). A better programmer would alter the php code of the Woocommerce site to interact with the API of a service like SMSGLOBAL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I made this website - tutorial</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/04/20/how-i-made-this-website---tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 14:12:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/04/20/how-i-made-this-website---tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Theory As our activities are increasingly organised online – from business through voting to leisure time – knowing how to write (or even just understand) code is an increasingly coveted skill. Its benefits range wide; if you can code you will get a better job, improve your analytical skills, make work processes easier and cheaper.
These reasons led us – Dora and Boaz, authors of this article – to set up our websites as a means of learning and practising a bit of coding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>