<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dataviz on Boaz Sobrado&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>http://boazsobrado.com/categories/dataviz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dataviz on Boaz Sobrado&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 09:58:21 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://boazsobrado.com/categories/dataviz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trumped: Cuba’s short term property rental market 2017-2018</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2019/02/19/trumped-cubas-short-term-property-rental-market-2017-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 09:58:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2019/02/19/trumped-cubas-short-term-property-rental-market-2017-2018/</guid>
      <description>In July of 2017 President Trump announced with much fanfare a new policy towards Cuba. This was following the Obama administrations &amp;ldquo;thaw&amp;rdquo; in Cuban-American bilateral relations, which had lead to a noticable rise in Americas visiting the island. Then more bad news for the Cuban tourism industry:
 sonic warfare in the news hurricanes  All of this together had a noticable impact on the Cuban tourism sector. Official Cuban statistics show that tourism numbers are going up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where I was in 2018</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2019/01/13/where-i-was-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 12:52:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2019/01/13/where-i-was-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>I spent a lot of time this year on the road. I started 2018 on a tropical beach in the Phillipines and ended it in Lisbon, with a lot of trips in between. Given that I spent a good part of this year playing around with maps for my thesis, I thought it would be fun to use my Google Location Services data to animate my movement this year. Here is the result:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get your Facebook messages into R</title>
      <link>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/10/29/how-to-get-your-facebook-messages-into-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/10/29/how-to-get-your-facebook-messages-into-r/</guid>
      <description>It is a truism that we live in the information age, yet on a day to day basis we engage remarkably little with insights on the personal information we create. Sure, Netflix shows you films you want to see, Amazon offers books you want to buy and Facebook shows you pictures of cats with boobs or whatever it is you tend to click on, but explicit purpose of that is to get your money.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>